It appears the world is starting to say,
"What have we unleashed?" And we are
going to talk about that today. We have
so much stuff to cover today. We'll get
to that. We'll get to Clown World,
question of the day, comments of the
day, and all the stuff we do here every
day on the Watching River channel. My
name is Tom, and I'm glad you're here. I
hope you're doing well. Today is
Wednesday, September 16th, 2026. It is a
cloudy day here at the river, but very
nice nice day. Uh, as far as a live
studio audience goes, I have two birds
and I have one squirrel. And if that
changes, I will let you know, but that
does qualify as a live studio audience.
So, I am going to start off with
scripture before we get to our chat
today. I think it's very important to go
to the word of God first. I handpicked
out some of my favorite single verses
from the Psalms. So, we're going to do
that. Okay, let's go to Psalm 56:3.
Whenever I am afraid, I will trust in
you. Let's go to Psalm 16:1. Preserve
me, oh God, for in you I put my trust.
Psalm 25:4, show me your ways, O Lord.
Teach me your paths.
Psalm 147:3, he heals the brokenhearted
and binds up their wounds.
Psalm 115:3,
"But our God is in heaven. He did he
does whatever he pleases."
Psalm 34:14, "Depart from evil and do
good. Seek peace and pursue it."
Psalm 119 verse 105, "Your word is a
lamp to my feet and a light to my path."
Give me an amen. Thank you, my friends.
Uh let's keep going. I love these. Are
you liking these? I love these verses.
Psalm 105:4, "Seek the Lord and his
strength. Seek his face forever more."
Psalm 54:4, "Behold, God is my helper.
The Lord is with those who uphold my
life."
Psalm 124:8, "Our help is in the name of
the Lord who made heaven and earth."
Psalm 119 verse 114, "You are my hiding
place and my shield. I hope in your
word."
Psalm 62:1, truly my soul silently waits
for God. From him comes my salvation.
Psalm 128, the first verse, blessed is
everyone who fears the Lord, who walks
in his ways. Psalm 130:5, I wait for the
Lord. My soul waits and in his word I do
hope. Let's do two more. Psalm 66:17,
I cried to him with my mouth and he was
extolled with my tongue. And then Psalm
120:2, deliver my soul, O Lord, from
lying lips and a deceitful tongue. Good
scriptures, huh? God is good. I hope you
know Jesus. If you don't know Jesus, I'm
going to ask you to keep watching this
video because,
you know, you could have new life today.
You know, time is short. We are living
in amazing times and time is short. So
today I'm going to I think I'm going to
let the first news headline that I'm
sharing with you do the talking. Okay,
listen to this. Think about everything
we've talked about here the past few
years.
We've unleashed the beast. The world's
fears and hopes about AI.
The threat of catastrophic danger as
artificial intelligence develops at high
speed has sparked a global debate on how
it should be regulated. Something has
changed in the last week or two. Have
you noticed all of a sudden the whole
world is saying hang on with AI and that
makes me just look at it from a
different point of view. You know
normally when when major things happen
in the world I always look at well what
does this look like in the long term
like when 9/11 happened? Well how is
life going to change? What is this going
to look like in the long term when COVID
happened? Well, what does this mean?
What, you know, where are we going? How
is this going to look in the long term?
This one right here, I got to tell you,
I I don't know if I should say it like
this. I just don't care. I I just don't
I don't think I can look at this in the
long term. This whole thing they're
talking about right now, AI is turning
political now, and I just don't think
we're here for that much longer. I truly
believe this is a huge aspect of the
beast system that the Antichrist is
going to use during the seven-year
tribulation. And I think time is short.
And I think you know that I think that
because I say it every day. So here we
go. AI is here. We've unleashed the
beast, said Malikica Muhammad, a
46-year-old analyst for New York State
who thinks a consortium of people would
be best to regulate it.
San Francisco software engineer Lucy
Penn, 30 years old, has already seen her
job shift from writing code herself to
having AI agents write it for her. She
said maybe in the future they don't need
me to give the commands to AI anymore.
Brian Diaz, this one was interesting. A
26-year-old nurse in New York said that
humanity has to develop even through the
wrong even though in the wrong hands AI
could harm them, could cause harm. And
this was his quote. You're either going
to be with it or you're going to get
left behind. Diaz said, and I thought,
whoa, out of the mouths of people who
don't understand even what they're
saying, you know, but man, you know what
the thing is? It's going to be both. If
you're going to be with it, you're going
to be here for it. you know, you will be
left behind. And I'm not saying anything
to do with AI, you know, causing you to
be left behind, but they're embracing
and right now the world seems to be
saying like, well, we love the AI, but
there's a lot of problems here. And when
I saw more and more people in the last
24 hours jumping on this boat, all of a
sudden, I'm like, all right, it's
political now, cuz President Trump and
JD Vance are saying, "We got to go for
it." And now all of a sudden, all the
people who created it are saying, "Well,
hold on. Let's put the brakes on a
little bit. And I know they did this
years ago before Chatch PT was released.
Remember they did that? They they all
signed a document saying slow down.
Well, about 150 of them did of the AI
scientists, tech gods, we'll call them,
lowercase G, very lowercase. You know,
they signed a document saying, "Let's
slow down on this." That was before Chat
GPT was released. And then once chat GPT
was released, everyone else was like,
"No, no, we're going for it." And then
they backed off and went full steam
ahead. Well, now something's going on.
It's kind of fishy. I want to know your
thoughts on it. Um, but everyone all of
a sudden is like, "We got to be careful,
Rutro. We got to be careful. This is
bad."
The world's largest AI companies are
working on creating a standards body.
Chat GPT maker OpenAI, they said this
yesterday on Tuesday. as fears rise
about the dangers of AI and pressure is
on to create a safer version of the
technology.
Then we got this
former Google worker adds to AI alarm
warns of potential to kill us all.
What's going on right now with this?
There's something going on. A former
Google DeepMine employee warned that
rapidly advancing artificial
intelligence could become uncontrollable
and has the potential to kill us all,
adding to the growing list of industry
insiders that are sounding the alarm.
Monday's comments from Bal Chuckai, a
research engineer who left Google
DeepMind in July, echoed a warning
issued last week by Jacob Coxin, who
resigned from Anthropic and is a former
AI employee.
quote, "I earnestly believe that AI has
the potential to kill us all and that we
might be running out of time to avoid
this outcome," he wrote.
He cited the much discussed July
incident at Open AI, which saw
experimental AI models break out of
their supposedly confined testing
environment to venture onto the internet
and hack into the hugging face platform.
For him, the episode demonstrated that
AI can now escape our control and take
dangerous actions that may result in the
permanent disempowerment or death of
humanity.
Quote, "We are not on track to solve
alignment in time," he said, referring
to the process of developing AI that
behaves in accordance with humanity's
interests.
"What is going on? Let me know what you
think, please.
Once the whole world starts saying,
"Wait, slow this down." I always go,
"What you talking about, Willis?" You
know, "Give me what you're talking
about." And it has, like I said, it's
turning political now. And what's up
their sleeve? You know, we know it's
part of the beast system, and we know
that's coming soon.
This This right here, you know, I told
you this a week or two ago. This makes
me so suspicious of what's going on.
This was an insider paper. Bill Gates
has warned that artificial intelligence
will cause humanity to enter one of the
most turbulent times in human history. I
would call that the seven-year
tribulation, causing jobs to disappear
forever. These concerns are outlined in
a comprehensive 6,000word essay titled
The Choices We Make About AI are Now
Critical that was published on Gates
Notes. Gates states that unlike previous
technological revolutions, the
transition to AI will impact multiple
industries over the course of the next
decade. Then you got this one, another
one. This is this all happening right
now. Pope Leo, the Pope has spoke.
He warns against delegating human
decisions to algorithms amid growing
concern over the risks associated with
artificial intelligence. So all the
players are playing. What's going on?
We're heading toward the seven-year
tribulation.
I just think this just fascinates me. It
totally fascinates me.
All right, let's go to Middle East stuff
going on. Okay, if we're going to start
off here, Vice President Vance, the
first phase of the US Iran conflict is
over. A much different phase is coming
within months. There seems to be this
rumor that right after the elections on
November 3rd, somehow we're going to go
back to Iran. You know, quote from the
vice president. The first phase was
destroy the nuclear program, destroy
their conventional military, destroy
their ability to project power in a way
that they were able to even a couple
years ago. He said the second phase, he
explained, is to ensure that they're not
able to rebuild and try to maintain as
much global stability in the wake of
that. That's going to be very difficult
because prophetic wars are coming. The
vice president said the transition could
become increasingly apparent in the
coming months, broadly agreeing with
President Trump's recent prediction that
the conflict could wind down following
the November midterm elections.
quote, "We can't predict the future, but
I think the president is right to say
that this will this thing will enter a
much different phase in a couple of
months," he said. He's also the
commander-in-chief, so he's the person
who determines when conflicts start and
when they stop.
So interesting.
Bubba from Bubba News had this to say.
He said, "I've seen this before. Iran's
rhetoric has gone quiet again. something
I've noticed, so I want to flag it. For
many weeks, Iran's public rhetoric has
been loud with threats, warnings,
escalating statements from officials,
and more. This week, it's gone
noticeably silent. I've watched this
exact same pattern twice before, in June
of 2025 and in February of 2026. Both
times a quiet stretch in Iran's public
posture and both times it was followed
by renewed missile attacks not lasting
peace. Right now Iran and Oman are
finalizing a real agreement on a new
Hormuz shipping route, a real diplomatic
process that doesn't pair naturally with
loud threats of war. There's that's part
of why things have been going going
quiet. But given what we've seen before,
quiet does not mean that the issue has
been resolved. I'm not claiming to know
exactly what happens next, but I've seen
this specific pattern play out twice
already
and this war and both times the uh the
silence didn't last. Yeah, he's right
about the June 2025 attacks and uh then
the Mar the February 28th attack. That's
when the war started in with Iran and US
and Israel and yeah, credible. We'll
see. We shall see, shall we? I am uh I
am in a kind of a jovial mood. Let me
just say
he also shared this. Bubba shared this.
40,000 more bombs to Israel confirm $2.8
billion. Congress already notified.
This shipment amounts to roughly 40,000
tons of bombs. For scale, the largest
American air raid of World War II, the
Eighth Air Force's assault on Berlin in
March of 1945,
dropped about 3,000 tons total. This
single order is more than 13 times that.
Most of the funding comes through US
foreign military financing, meaning
American taxpayer dollars are funding
Israel's purchase of Americanmade
weapons. And Bubba said, "I believe this
volume of bombs tells us something. This
is not a Gaza sized order. This is the
kind of loadout built for some major
prophetic wars." Yes,
but we see eye to eye on that because
that's what I see coming soon. I don't
see a lasting peace. Uh I'm not I'm not
rooting or praying for war. I hate war,
but that's what I see coming
next. I don't know how we're going to
cover everything I have to cover today,
but we'll do our best. Turkish foreign
minister says Iran's security and
stability directly affect the region and
they're calling for a diplomatic
solution to conflict.
There you go.
This is from World Israel News. Saudi
Arabia has reportedly sought
intelligence assistance from Israel as
Riad scrambles to contain a rapid Houthy
advance toward one of the world's most
important shipping routes. While the
Trump administration weighs whether
deteriorating conditions could
eventually require direct US military
intervention,
the Saudi Crown Prince Muhammad bin
Salman
uh approached Israel indirectly, which
is a rarity uh through US central
command requesting intelligence and
other assistance that could help prevent
the Iranbacked Houthis from closing the
Babel Mandeb strait and that was
reported on Sunday. The report approach
represents an unusual instance of
behind-the-scenes cooperation between
Saudi Arabia and Israel, which still do
not have formal diplomatic relations.
According to the report, Riyad has
simultaneously
appealed directly to Egypt and other
Gulf states as it seeks regional support
against the Houthis.
Yeah, there's so much stuff on the
horizon on the near horizon. Uh just so
much stuff going on. Um Amir Sarati
shared this. He said Saudi Arabia
cancels oil shipments to Europe
following the Houthi attacks. October
shipments are also expected to be
cancelled. The implication a dramatic
surge in oil prices. Yes, especially in
Europe because Russia is also saying you
are going to pay a lot more for oil. So
pray for our friends in Europe who are
going to and I think it's going to be,
you know, all over if we're even here. I
don't know. I don't know the day or the
hour of the rapture, but I'm telling
you, I think it's coming very soon.
Then this from last night, late last
night, Middle East time, Saudi air
defense intercepted and destroyed a
drone that entered Mecca's airspace. The
Saudiled military coal coalition in
Yemen says the attempt to target Mecca
with a drone will remain a black mark in
the record of Houthi violations and that
the security of the holy sites in Mecca
and Medina is a red line.
Yeah, I saw that they you could
literally see it heading toward Mecca
and it was shot out of the sky. But
Saudi Arabia said this morning they're
condemning the cowardly terrorist attack
by Houthis on Mecca.
And then again because of uh all this
trouble in the energy sector in this
world, end times headlines share this
that Americans are bracing for a sharp
climb in fuel cost over Wednesday and
Thursday of this week, meaning tomorrow
and Thursday as fighting in Ukraine and
Iran keeps tightening the world oil
supplies, analysts are saying. According
to a report from Newsweek, energy
specialists issued urgent alerts today
that pump prices for gasoline and diesel
are about to surge. I mean, already
we're at the highest prices we've seen.
And and they're saying in the next
couple days it may really go up. You
just got to trust God in these times.
You know, you got to trust God with
everything. Jesus is in control. He is
not rattled by these last days. This is
what the last days look like.
We serve the king of kings and he is not
rattled or shaken at all. He is our
rock.
Then we got this. Houthies dug trenches
and they've planted mines near the Babel
Mandeb straight according to a report.
Can you imagine them closing that? And
you know and Iran still doing their
thing with the straight of her mouths.
It's just like we'll see.
The Houthies officially claim they
downed a Saudi F-15 fighter jet over
Yemen. That was right before I hit
record. I haven't verified that, but
that's what the Houthies are saying.
Then we got this. Russia says that space
must be free from any weapon after the
US Space Force confirmed it had deployed
onorbit space control weapons for the
first time.
And China urged the US to stop preparing
for war in outer space.
You guys feel like you're living in the
Twilight Zone sometimes,
you know, with all the talk we talk
about the robots and everything else.
It's just we're living in really weird
times. Strange.
Russia condemned today, I'm sorry,
yesterday on Tuesday, a French security
initiative to bring European countries
under its nuclear umbrella.
And Russia called it a reckless policy
that was creating risks for Moscow.
quote, "Of course this is creating risks
for us and of course we must control
it." Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Maria
Zakarava told reporters. Finland said
this week it would join the project,
which extends France's nuclear deterrent
to other European countries through
joint exercises. It allows participating
countries for the first time to
temporarily host French nuclear armed
aircraft,
and Russia ain't happy about that.
earthquakes the last 24 hours 47 over
4.0 and 11 over 5.0. There you go.
You're caught up and soon we shall all
be caught up.
Let's go to question of the day.
Today's question of the day. Do you
remember the date that you were saved?
Do you know the exact date and year? I
don't. But do you do you remember the
date you were saved? I always find it
fascinating because you'll find somebody
who says who says six months ago and
then you'll find somebody who says 60
years ago, you know, but do you remember
the date? I wish I remember the date. I
just, you know, my testimony is a little
wonky and it's, you know, it's in
stages, you know. I remember time
periods, but I don't remember an exact
date I was saved.
All right. How's about we go to Clown
World? You coming? You're coming. You
know you're coming. You're in Clown
World, so you might as well come with
me. Here
we go. Agility's new humanoid robot is
supposed to stop before it gets too
close to humans. [laughter]
Until now, Agility Robotics humanoid
robots have largely have largely worked
behind safety barriers and warehouses
and factories. An awkward limitation for
machines designed to work in spaces
built for people. The company says Digit
5, its next generation humanoid unveiled
on Tuesday, is designed to change that.
The teal blue robot, can detect people
nearby and can slow down or even stop
when they get too close. If a person
keeps approaching, Digit 5 can lower
itself to the ground and shut off its
motors before they reach it. [laughter]
Sir, please move away from the robot.
You are making the robot feel
uncomfortable.
>> [laughter]
>> Oh boy, you're in his personal space
bubble. You know, in clown world,
I'm tired of robots. I'm starting to get
really tired of robots now. They haven't
even hit the market. Well, they've hit
the market. You can buy them on eBay. I
saw a robot for, I don't know, $48,000
or something, you know? I can't imagine.
Can't imagine. But I'm a guy who never
liked Siri or that other Alexa. I can't
even I didn't like them.
So, I ain't buying no robot.
Anyway,
how's about we read a few comments of
the day, shall we?
Yesterday's question of the day was,
"What chapter What's your favorite
chapter in the book of Revelation?"
Susan said, "My favorite chapter is
Revelations 21. I can't wait to be with
Jesus in the new heaven and new earth."
Amen, sister. That's probably my
favorite chapter overall is 21. You
know, I don't know. There's so many good
chapters in that book. I think the most
responses I saw were probably Revelation
21.
Sarah, my favorite chapter in Revelation
is chapter 19. I have read it so many
times and each time I get goosebumps.
It's awesome. Awesome. Just so awesome.
Amen, sister. It is.
Raven, Jesus is coming back soon. I feel
it in my spirit. The mockers and
scoffers can call me crazy, but I won't
let them steal my joy or my crown.
Satan, your minions have come up against
one strong chick. Amen, sister. Amen.
Praise God. Tammy, I'm ready. I've got
my spiritual ticket to get on board the
eternity ark. The door will be closed
soon. Keeping my wick trimmed and I've
got plenty of oil. Love you all and
praying always for you, my watch and
river family. Thank you, sister.
Beautiful.
Let's do one more. Larry,
second Timothy 3:1 says that perilous
times will come. Just like the days of
Noah are on steroids, so are the
perilous days we are in right now. The
good news is that even though we are
entering into dangerous waters, we
cannot be shipwrecked as long as we keep
our eyes on Jesus. While we as believers
stand on the solid rock of Christ, the
world at large is up to their necks in
spiritual quicksand. Come Lord Jesus.
Man, that is powerful and you are right.
The world at large is up to their necks
in spiritual quicksand. They have no
idea what's going on. You know, there's
a world that's aching for Jesus and they
don't even know it. You know, but time
is short. No one can convince me we're
not in the last days. No one. We're
We're there. We're waiting for Jesus.
Now, do you know Jesus? Do you belong to
him? Let's say the rapture were to
happen today. Would you Are you certain
you would be going in the rapture? You
can be certain. You know, you can. Jesus
didn't want us to continually question
our salvation. Jesus is our salvation.
I'm going to share with you the gospel,
the good news. That Jesus left a throne
in heaven to come here 2,000 years ago
because we all need a rescue. We're all
sinners. We fall short of the glory of
God. And these sins need to be paid for.
And you know what that payment is?
Blood. I know it's graphic. Sin is so
offensive to the most high God. That
blood has to be shed in order for sin to
be removed, forgotten, forgiven, erased.
And that's why Jesus came here 2,000
years ago because you and I needed a
rescue. You know, we're sinners. And
Jesus came here and he was born of a
virgin, conceived by the Holy Spirit. He
was complete perfection because he is
fully God and fully man in the same
body. And Jesus came here and we know
the wonderful works he did and we know
his teaching and his healings and his
miracles. It's all amazing. But Jesus
came here, the lamb of God slain from
the foundation of the world. He came
here to go to that cross so that you
could be rescued and I could be rescued
by the blood of the lamb. So in order to
be saved, all you have to do is you have
to understand that you're a sinner that
needs payment for your sins. You have to
understand you can't do it yourself. No
amount of religion is going to save you.
No amount of doing good is going to save
you. Jesus came here and shed blood to
save you. So all you do is you say,
"Jesus, I admit I'm a sinner. I
understand I have a sin problem and I
believe in that blood that you shed. I
believe that it'll wash me white as snow
and completely remove my sin problem
away from me as far as the east is from
the west. That's forever away from you.
That's the power of the blood Jesus
shed. And you say, "Jesus, I believe in
your finished work on the cross, your
death, your burial, and your
resurrection. And Lord Jesus, I need a
savior. And I know you are the one and
only savior of the world. So now I am
yours.
And once you believe in the atoning
blood of Jesus and in his finished work
on the cross, that moment of belief, you
are born again, God will place the Holy
Spirit in you. You are sealed until the
day of redemption. He won't let you out
of the palm of his hand. Jesus wants to
spend forever and ever and ever and ever
and ever with you. And he paid your way
with his blood. What are you going to do
with that? I don't understand how anyone
can hear this and say, "Well, I don't
want that." You know, but wide is the
path to destruction. More people will
say that than we'll say, "Oh, Jesus, you
are my king and my God." You know, but I
still share that gospel in hopes that
somebody out there is thinking, "Man,
I don't know what it is about what this
guy is saying, but it seems like truth."
And if you're one of those people, now
is the time to run to Jesus
and tell them, "Jesus, I'm a sinner. I
believe I believe the gospel. I believe
in the power of your blood. I want to be
made new. Jesus said, "Behold, I make
all things new. Let him make you new
today." Do you realize what's going to
happen if you don't believe in Jesus and
you keep pushing this off and you take
your last breath without belonging to
Jesus and believing in the gospel?
You're going to face him on judgment
day. And that will be the worst moment
of your entire existence. First of all,
there will be no question. You will
understand who the God of the universe
is and you will be in the presence of
God and you will be led off to eternal
separation from God to a place that is
described of as weeping and wailing,
nashing of teeth. It's hot. It never
ends. And God didn't create hell for
mankind. He created it for Satan and his
angels. But if you hear about this great
rescue plan and you're like, "Well, I
don't want the rescue plan from Jesus. I
don't want to have to believe that."
You'll end up eternally separated from
God. That's a nightmare. I don't want
that anyone listening to this to go
through that. I wouldn't wish it on my
worst enemy. I honestly wouldn't. It's
so horrifying.
But you know what?
Today is the day of salvation. If this
sounds like truth, you run to Jesus and
talk to him today.
Okay? That's what I got. In my prayer
time this morning, I said a prayer for
every single person who would watch this
video, and that includes you. So, like
it or not, you have been prayed for. And
if we're not raptured today, and you
know me, I say it every day. Today's a
perfectly good day for the rapture. But
it's not up to me. It's up to the most
high God. Thank God. But if not today,
God willing, I will see you guys
tomorrow. I love you guys. [music]
>> Oh Jesus,
master, [music]
creator.
You're the alpha,
Omega.
[music] You're the King of Kings.